Who Needs A Heart When A Heart Can Be Broken?
What's Love Got to Do with It is a drama, music,
history film directed by Brian Gibson.
Singer Tina Turner rises to stardom while mustering the
courage to break free from her abusive husband Ike.
Anna Mae Bullock / Tina Turner, played by Angela Bassett.
Ike Turner, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Jackie, played by Vanessa Bell Calloway.
Zelma Bullock, played by Jenifer Lewis.
Darlene, played by Khandi Alexander.
Ike Turner Jr., played by Richard T. Jones.
What's Love Got to Do with It is a 1993 American biographical film
based on the life of singer-songwriter Tina Turner.
Directed by Brian Gibson and written by Kate Lanier from an uncredited story draft by the late Howard Ashman, based on Tina's 1986
autobiography I, Tina, it stars Angela Bassett as Tina and Laurence Fishburne as her abusive husband Ike Turner.
What's Love Got to Do with It premiered in Los Angeles on June 6, 1993, and was
theatrically released by Touchstone Pictures on June 25, 1993.
Although the Turners disapproved of its inaccuracies, the film was critically and
commercially successful, grossing $61 million on a $15 million budget.
For their performances, Bassett and Fishburne received nominations at
the 66th Academy Awards for Best Actress and Best Actor.
Bassett also won the Golden Globe Award for Best
Actress – Motion Picture Comedy or Musical.
The film explores themes of 1970s, affectation, record
producer, biography, recording studio.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.